There's a reason two people can share
the exact same story, the same event,
same information, sometimes even [music]
the same words. However, one gets people
leaning in and the other gets nothing.
For years, people called it the it
factor, as if you had it or you just
didn't. Turns out, it's actually not
that mysterious. [music]
It's a handful of decisions made in a
specific order and once you see them,
you can't unsee them. Once I started
looking for it, I saw it everywhere. In
that viral [music] video on my TikTok
for you page, man speech, and that one
coworker that everyone stops to listen
to. It's the same handful of moves on
repeat, but knowing those moves and
actually teaching those moves so that
someone else can [music] learn them is
apparently a completely different
problem. What I'm talking about is
storytelling and I got the idea to share
this knowledge with as many people as
possible. [music] I decided to launch
the storytelling content challenge where
I'll be handing you the perfect daily
post to grow the [music] right audience.
Now, what I didn't know is just how much
work this was going to be. For the past
6 weeks, I've been away [music] from
those I love working 20-hour days and
barely sleeping. And now with the
deadline almost here, all that's
standing between me and making this idea
[music] reality is one more really early
morning and 18 very important tasks on
my to-do list. This is a video about
whether any of this actually holds up.
Starting now, [music] 18 hours of work
and a task for every hour. I miss even
one, I owe you 20 push-ups. Not really
because the push-ups matter at all, but
because I want to hold myself to a
standard and I want you to keep me
accountable. Because if I can't hold
myself to a standard, then how can I ask
you to trust what I'm building for you?
It is 3:51 a.m. and the first task is to
send over deck briefings to my designer.
These are videos that will actually live
within the program.
>> [music]
>> It's safe to say an hour was a little
ambitious to get all of this done, but
it is 3:00 in the morning, so forgive
me. I wasn't that far off, but rules are
rules.
Ah, shoot.
I'm 12 minutes late.
You know what that means.
>> It's 5:12 a.m. And now the goal is to
get a workout in, shower, and actually
look presentable for the rest of the
day.
Today is pool day, and the gym might not
seem like an essential for the whole
work task, [music] but I do find it
gives me energy and allows me to
maximize focus and efficiency all day
long.
Done.
We did it.
Today breakfast was yogurt, eggs, and
ketchup. [music]
And in all honesty, I eat the exact same
thing every single morning. And it also
gives me time for some journaling before
the next [music] work block. I just sent
over the brief for the decks, and it's
with my designer. However, I still have
to add several examples of how to
utilize the frameworks. So, yeah, the
next hour
until 7:45 a.m., I am just going to make
sure that the team understands exactly
how to utilize these frameworks. And
it's going to matter for the copy of the
landing pages, our copy for the emails,
and things like that. So, yeah, wish me
luck.
As the team gets bigger, I have to get
even better at delegating, and creating
these master docs and briefs is a big
part of this.
Some things that aren't going as they
should be this morning. And it's the
reality, but we failed again.
Okay, I'm back. The SD card filled up,
and then I was using my phone to record,
but I needed it to actually post the
morning carousel. But it's uploaded, and
it's 8:41 a.m. Now, for the next hour, I
want to get over two recordings for
content that will live within the
challenge. And basically, these will be
Loom recordings. I'll use my main cam
here, but do a presentation deck on this
side. So, wish me luck. You can't really
tell this time lapse, but let's just say
one of those looms took me many more
attempts than I could have expected and
now I'm a bit behind. All right, quick
update. I got one out of the two done.
You You just saw how many times I messed
up and that's like always the case. Some
days I have it, some days I don't. This
is one of the days I just don't have it
and I hope the next one is better, but
I'm going to do some push-ups to make
amends.
Okay, so I did forget to record, but I
promise I actually did the push-ups.
10:05 a.m. I have to in the next 55
minutes get over a loom to the team
detailing the next slide brief cuz the
editors need to be on it and it's I'm a
little behind in that I'm actually quite
a lot behind that. So, I got to do that
now. It's going to change some of the
order things around cuz I wasn't
planning to do it now. As boring as it
sounds, I feel like my life lives on
these three apps, Miro, Slack and Loom.
That worked. Not only did I just fully
brief, [music] I also actually recorded
it and sent it over. So, good spot. I I
feel like I'm making up some ground. For
the next hour we have an interview
and so we're about to kick that off
right now.
We just finished up basically a briefing
of how we felt coming out of that
interview, me and Alex, because he works
directly on our content that we have a
lot in common in terms of our goals and
we also are going to be working together
all the time with that additional hire.
So, we just kind of went through our
thoughts together. It was very
productive and now I'm in a spot where I
got to review some emails.
So, a quick little intermission. We are
surprising my editor
with a brand new MacBook Pro with all
the bells and whistles. And he's worked
so hard and he deserves it. Just a quick
little token of appreciation.
I'm excited.
>> Let's go.
Okay, eyes closed. Eyes Don't Don't
Don't open it.
>> I know.
Wait, actually then I'll record on my
phone, too. Once again, keep your eyes
closed. Keep your eyes closed.
2 1
You can look.
I might have lied, but I got you a new
MacBook Pro.
>> What?
>> [laughter]
>> This is my gift to you,
>> [music]
>> and it's for all of your hard work, and
I feel like this is just a token of the
appreciation. [music] This has all the
bells and whistles, every
I believe upgrade that I could have
done, I think.
And this is just me personally to you
for everything that you've done for last
9 months.
>> Oh, it's Oh my goodness.
>> Yeah, I had nothing else to do, but
I don't know what
>> I was like I don't know how to smell it
out, too. Give it to you.
>> Think it's a surprise if
>> He's opening it.
>> I know.
>> You deserve it, and I I couldn't be more
blessed that I've [music] had you on my
team, and
um it's it's like a small token of
everything that you've done for me.
>> I appreciate it, Justin.
>> Yeah, man. Thank you so much.
>> You absolutely do.
>> Claudio's going to get
>> No, Claudio's going
>> We have the next hour to work on story
posts have to go up, and actually I got
to I got to check. I don't know even
know what
what I am supposed to be doing at this
point. Um
Oh, the VSLs. I haven't even start
started them. Okay, I will be doing that
now for the next
uh 55 minutes. Hopefully I get
one to two VSLs filmed.
If I don't get these VSLs done before
Change of plans, I'm reviewing some
carousels. Ah, that that deserves some
push-ups.
>> After finally getting those push-ups
done, I spent 2 hours filming ads,
reviewing content with Alex before
moving on to the most important thing on
today's to-do list, which is movie night
with my girlfriend. Because I want to
make sure she knows that she's still a
big priority in my life.
And I couldn't do any of this without
her.
Movie time.
>> [music]
>> It is officially the end of the day, so
we have some counting to do. First on
screen, you have the total number of
push-ups that I did as punishment for
the day. Not too bad, actually. It was
quite rough in the morning, but I
started to pick up some momentum later
on in the day. Now, in regards to the
current time, it is 12:32 a.m. I believe
we started around 3:30 a.m. the day
before. Today was another 18-hour day.
That also means the total number of
hours for this challenge spent has been
541 hours to build this, and I think the
daily average probably goes up a little
bit as well. So, that's the day in the
life. It takes what it takes, and
I hope it's all worth it.
I'm going to take that back. I'm going
to take I know it'll be worth it.